### MOHAMMAD KABIR ABDULSALAM

# **Software Engineer**

Berlin 10715, Germany | (+49) 179 103 9415 | mkab.abdulsalam@gmail.com | https://github.com/mkab

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

A highly successful Software Engineer with 4 years of commercial experience in a variety of software development and architectural positions. I have a strong experience implementing and developing APIs. I have built various customer facing features that increased both the conversion and retention rates of customers and drove the product vision for the various companies I worked at.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Technologies: Python, Java, PHP, JavaScript,

Data Management: PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Redis

JQuery, SQL

Frameworks: Django, CSS Bootstrap, libGDX

Web technologies: REST, Web Sockets, HTML, CSS

Monitoring tools: New Relic, Grafana, Kibana, Sentry

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **Software Engineer (November 2018 – Present)**

#### Delivery Hero – Berlin, Germany (one of the leading global online food ordering and delivery platforms)

- Developed a Loyalty Point system and an API to interact with it. The service and its API are being used by other software engineers, including me, in the company to create loyalty program campaigns. This improved the retention rate of many of our customers by 30 % and made them more loyal to our platform.
- Revamped the current billing system for restaurants that use our platform. This helped the company to be more transparent with what it bills the restaurants and in turn, helped the restaurants to better understand their invoices.
- Worked closely with Product Managers to design and structure new projects that improve customer retention rates
- On-boarded junior software engineers, coached them on the tools and services we use and guided them through the codebase.

Tools/Tech used: Python, Django, Celery, Docker, PostgreSQL, Kubernetes, GCP, New Relic, Kibana, Sentry, Grafana, Git

## Solution Strategist (September 2017 - August 2018)

### Peach Aviation - Osaka, Japan (3<sup>rd</sup> largest Airline in Japan)

- Designed and implemented a RESTful API used by third parties to retrieve the company's flight data for any period of time.
- Implemented a near real-time flight status system by creating a RESTful API that fetches data either from the database or from a cache. This system updates itself every 5 minutes and also displays future flight data, which are flights that are scheduled 6 days in advance. It is mainly used by the pilots and cabin attendants to schedule their shifts for the week and by business analysts to get real time data when needed.
- Installation and maintenance of airport counters and self-check-in kiosks at new flight destinations.
- Designed and develop a GDPR compliant pilot/cabin attendant recruitment platform. The platform records the relevant data potential candidates and provides the data in a user-friendly usable for recruiters. It enables them, among other things, to easily search for candidates, rate them on various criteria such as soft and hard skills and aggregate the whole data to on certain criteria which can help them to make a decision on which candidate to hire.

Tools/Tech used: PHP, Python, Google Apps Script, Google Cloud Platform, Google Big Query, MySQL, JQuery, CSS Bootstrap

## Server-side Engineer (January 2016 - July 2017)

# Platinum Egg – Osaka, Japan (Video Game Company – creates mobile and web-based games)

- Developed a system to manage company-related tasks such as employee work statistics and job reports
- Designed various game campaigns such as Christmas, New Year's, and valentine campaigns.
- Improved the performance of the battle matchmaking by 25% using Redis which made users to quickly find opponents
- Improved the time taken for the weekly deployment (which was mainly done using Python scripts) by 30%
- Created a web scraper that scrapes websites for relevant statistical data and downloads CSV files from these said sites. The program further crunches the data and uses it to update the company's KPI spreadsheets.
- Utilized Jenkins to run automated tests. This improved the rate at which we shipped new features to our users.

Tools/Tech used: Python, pytest, Django, Redis, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, MySQL, Git, Docker, Jenkins, JIRA

|             | Education                                   |  |
|-------------|---|--|
| 2013 – 2015 | Master's in Software Engineering            | Université Pierre et Marie Curie – Paris, France |
| 2012 – 2013 | Master's in Computer Science                | Université de Marne-la-Vallée, France            |
| 2009 – 2012 | Bachelor's in Computer Science              | Université de Cergy-Pontoise – Cergy, France     |
| 1999 – 2005 | WAEC (Secondary School Leaving Certificate) | Zamani College – Kaduna, Nigeria                 |

Hobbies: Football, cycling, table tennis, chess

Languages: Fluent in French and upper-intermediate level in Japanese (JLPT N3 certificate acquired)